<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>econ on ariana&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>/tags/econ/</link>
    <description>Recent content in econ on ariana&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 23:30:37 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/econ/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>small loans for big dreams: how TaiLong Bank winning both the hearts and the markets</title>
      <link>/posts/lending_money_to_small_business/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 23:30:37 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/lending_money_to_small_business/</guid>
      <description>In choosing between issuing a 1-billion loan to one massive state-owned enterprise or lending 1 million to a thousand smaller companies, most would prefer the first option as it seems more convenient and reliable. However, Zhejiang Tailong Commercial Bank (TaiLong Bank) takes the less-traveled path – the bank provides financial services to small-and-micro-enterprises (SMEs). Since its inception, the bank has cumulatively provided over ¥150 billion (around $23 billion) in loans, with an average loan size of ¥500,000, to its clientele, over 90% of whom are peasants-turned-entrepreneurs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a scholarship visit to TaiLong bank - discovering their business model in an out</title>
      <link>/posts/a_visit_to_tailong_bank/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 23:39:16 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/a_visit_to_tailong_bank/</guid>
      <description>Zhejiang Tailong Commercial Bank (TLB) is the most renowned Small-and-Medium-sized Enterprise (SME) financing service provider in China. TLB has invested over ¥100 million in its charity fund and consistently allocates 2% of its revenue to its foundation. I was fortunate to receive a scholarship sponsored by TLB and even more so to be invited to their headquarters today for a face-to-face meeting with their chairman and the leaders of the Shanghai Branch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>prologue | kidney exchange 101</title>
      <link>/posts/kidney_exchange101/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 23:20:40 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/kidney_exchange101/</guid>
      <description>When opportunity comes, say, when you find yourself sharing an elevator with a Nobel Prize winner in your field, with just a few floors left to impress them. It&amp;rsquo;s sales pitch in academic–to impress people using a concise, compelling summary that highlights the brilliance and relevance of your work. It&amp;rsquo;s your chance to leave them thinking, &amp;ldquo;Wow, I need to know more about this!&amp;rdquo;
In my journey, I often find myself needing to explain kidney exchange to introduce people to market design—my dream field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>the looming crisis in maternity care - a tale of two nations</title>
      <link>/posts/news_cmi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 23:06:37 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/news_cmi/</guid>
      <description>The maternity care units in both the United States and China are facing a dilemma that threatens the very foundation of obstetric services. This crisis, while nuanced in its manifestation in each country, shares a common thread of financial strain, staffing challenges, and misaligned incentives that put the future of maternity care at risk.
The American Struggle
In the United States, the situation is particularly dire in rural areas, where more than 200 hospitals have closed their labor and delivery services over the past decade.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>case mix index (CMI) explained</title>
      <link>/posts/cmi_as_an_incentive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 23:29:22 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/cmi_as_an_incentive/</guid>
      <description>Imagine you&amp;rsquo;re analyzing a group of general undergraduates taking math classes. Some are social science majors who might be taking introductory statistics, while others are engineering majors taking advanced calculus. You need some index to measure the average difficulty level of the math classes taken by all these students, say, Stats101 for 1pt while Real Analysis gets 10pt and we&amp;rsquo;ll take arithmetic mean as the difficulty score representing the general course level taken by all the students.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>an (intentional?) refund loophole in TaoBao</title>
      <link>/posts/refund_bug/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 23:26:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/refund_bug/</guid>
      <description>In the curious world of TaoBao, China&amp;rsquo;s e-commerce giant, I stumbled upon what can only be described as a &amp;ldquo;feature&amp;rdquo; cleverly masquerading as a bug. Once in a while, TaoBao hosts what’s known as the &amp;ldquo;cross-seller price-break discount.&amp;rdquo; In theory, this sounds like a standard promotional sale—spend a certain amount across various sellers, and voila, you snag a discount. For instance, rack up items totaling 300 yuan from participating sellers, and you’re treated to a 40 yuan discount.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>the market power of higher education</title>
      <link>/posts/market_power_of_college/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 23:53:25 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/market_power_of_college/</guid>
      <description>Today&amp;rsquo;s blog draws inspiration from Michael D. Smith&amp;rsquo;s perspective on higher education, as discussed in a recent episode of the podcast People I (Mostly) Admire, titled &amp;ldquo;Higher Education Is Broken. Can It Be Fixed?&amp;rdquo; . Btw, the podcast itself is part of the Freakonomics network, the academically inclined perspective is particularly sweetspot for an econ student.
This episode elucidates the systemic flaws plaguing the U.S. higher education system. One pov involves diving into the market power of colleges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>measuring information and uncertainty</title>
      <link>/posts/measuring_information_and_uncertainty2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 23:03:45 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/measuring_information_and_uncertainty2/</guid>
      <description>buckle up for deep revelation</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
