<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>art on ariana&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>/tags/art/</link>
    <description>Recent content in art on ariana&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 20:57:08 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/art/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>eclipsed revelation - crafting eternal sunshine in keystrokes</title>
      <link>/posts/eternal_sunshine_themeable/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 20:57:08 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/eternal_sunshine_themeable/</guid>
      <description>Inspired by the aesthetic of eternal sunshine&amp;rsquo;s album cover, I customized a Typora themeable that echos the album&amp;rsquo;s concept.
the red of the gloves, paired with the innocent white dress, echoes a juxtaposition of passion and purity. meanwhile The dark background augments the sense of mesmerizing self-revelation.
Instead of directly replicating the color palette from the album cover, I decided to take a more conceptual approach, in reflecting the commitment to an ethereal minimalism—like, an homage to the what Saturn Return brings into our lives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saturn return</title>
      <link>/posts/saturn_return/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 23:08:02 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/saturn_return/</guid>
      <description>When we&amp;rsquo;re all born, Saturn&amp;rsquo;s somewhere. And the Saturn cycle takes around about 29 years. That&amp;rsquo;s when we&amp;rsquo;ve gotta wake up and smell the coffee. Because if we&amp;rsquo;ve just been sort of relying on our cleverness, or relying, you know, just kind of floating along&amp;hellip; Saturn comes along and hits you over the head, and says, &amp;ldquo;Wake up&amp;rdquo;.
It&amp;rsquo;s time for you to get real about life And sort out who you really are.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a study of the lowercase aesthetic</title>
      <link>/posts/lowercase_aesthetic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 20:09:56 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/lowercase_aesthetic/</guid>
      <description>I prefer writing in all lowercases–especially devoid of conventional capitalizations of the first letters. First learnt this in Ariana Grande&amp;rsquo;s Sweetener album tracks&amp;rsquo; all-lowercase namings and initially trying just for fun, I found this way of styled writing extremely comfortable so that it eventually forms into a habit. This seemingly personal preference however, coincides with a latest trend of writing style, especially among Gen Z.
Ariana Grande&amp;rsquo;s iconic, abusive use of all-lowercase writings in her social media posts, do do her fans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>the first amendment | ariana&#39;s blog </title>
      <link>/posts/the_first_amendment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 18:32:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the_first_amendment/</guid>
      <description>what to look forward</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>the IDGAS energy in Sabrina Carpenter&#39;s &#39;Nonsense&#39;</title>
      <link>/posts/nonsense/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 11:00:59 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/nonsense/</guid>
      <description>Sabrina Carpenter&amp;rsquo;s hit Nonsense is a great song, both artistically and commercially. The song gives a &amp;ldquo;I-DONT-GIVE-A-SHIT&amp;rdquo; (IDGAS) energy. The singer herself said in Genius VERIFIED interview
&amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;we were hitting a lot of walls and we&amp;rsquo;re like, you know what, let&amp;rsquo;s just literally write nonsense, no joke. and that&amp;rsquo;s how the song happened.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;A lot of our justification for lyrics was well it&amp;rsquo;s nonsense. so it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to make any sense at all and we just have fun.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
