<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>nonsense on ariana&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>/tags/nonsense/</link>
    <description>Recent content in nonsense on ariana&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 00:16:23 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/nonsense/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>cloying your employees – or their parents?</title>
      <link>/posts/cloying_your_employees/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 00:16:23 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/cloying_your_employees/</guid>
      <description>Another day, another mountain of literature on boosting employee productivity and fostering workplace belonging. It&amp;rsquo;s almost as if we&amp;rsquo;re running out of ways to say the same thing. Building on yesterday&amp;rsquo;s discussion, my visit to TaiLong Bank unveiled an innovative practice that has proven effective—engaging employees&amp;rsquo; parents.
TaiLong Bank operates with a decentralized structure, empowering branches and sub-branches with significant autonomy. Notably, over 80% of loan decisions are made at the sub-branch level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a scholarship visit to TaiLong bank - discovering their business model in an out</title>
      <link>/posts/a_visit_to_tailong_bank/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 23:39:16 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/a_visit_to_tailong_bank/</guid>
      <description>Zhejiang Tailong Commercial Bank (TLB) is the most renowned Small-and-Medium-sized Enterprise (SME) financing service provider in China. TLB has invested over ¥100 million in its charity fund and consistently allocates 2% of its revenue to its foundation. I was fortunate to receive a scholarship sponsored by TLB and even more so to be invited to their headquarters today for a face-to-face meeting with their chairman and the leaders of the Shanghai Branch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saturn return</title>
      <link>/posts/saturn_return/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 23:08:02 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/saturn_return/</guid>
      <description>When we&amp;rsquo;re all born, Saturn&amp;rsquo;s somewhere. And the Saturn cycle takes around about 29 years. That&amp;rsquo;s when we&amp;rsquo;ve gotta wake up and smell the coffee. Because if we&amp;rsquo;ve just been sort of relying on our cleverness, or relying, you know, just kind of floating along&amp;hellip; Saturn comes along and hits you over the head, and says, &amp;ldquo;Wake up&amp;rdquo;.
It&amp;rsquo;s time for you to get real about life And sort out who you really are.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>just like magic</title>
      <link>/posts/just_like_magic2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:53:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/just_like_magic2/</guid>
      <description>Ariana Grande possesses a magnetic energy that attracts literally everything–from musical excellence to (possibly undesired) publicity. Among her songs, &amp;ldquo;just like magic&amp;rdquo; stands out as a testament to awe-inspiring confidence:
Just like magic, I&amp;rsquo;m attractive
I get everything I want cause I attract them.
There&amp;rsquo;s a fine line between positive self-assurance and complacency. With her four-octave range and Mariah Carey-like whistle note capacity, Ariana Grande has never lacked a &amp;ldquo;hear-me-roar&amp;rdquo; attitude, reminiscent of &amp;rsquo;90s divas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>34&#43;35</title>
      <link>/posts/34_35/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 23:59:50 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/34_35/</guid>
      <description>means i wanna sixty-nine with yu, no&amp;hellip;shit
(mumbling) math class, never was good
– 34+35, Positions
Living under possibly the most draconian public scrutiny, Ariana Grande steered through the tumulous years of her rising music career accompanied by a terrorist attack during tour, several relationship melt downs, meanwhile delivered two of the best albums—and one of the highest-grossing tours—of 2018 and 2019. That she might finally be experiencing some release, which is what her return album in 2020 Positions sound like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>needy</title>
      <link>/posts/needy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 23:08:46 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/needy/</guid>
      <description>Thank U, Next got two seats out of the top-10 list. One is imagine, the other is needy.
I do hate overly simple songs: cloying melodies consisted of banal, unimaginative motifs and too-obvious intentions are absolutely unforgivable. Referring the words of a professor&amp;rsquo;s architecture appreciation course I&amp;rsquo;ve taken two years ago, &amp;ldquo;sometimes overly obvious &amp;lsquo;signs&amp;rsquo; or too straightforward expressions, despite appealing, are degrading for art.&amp;rdquo;
BUT &amp;mdash;- despite having shallow melodies (that one can literally anticipate the whole song after hearing the first few bars), needy sits on top of the list being simplicitly expressive and truthful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>imagine</title>
      <link>/posts/imagine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 23:55:46 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/imagine/</guid>
      <description>As the opening track of Ariana Grande&amp;rsquo;s tumultuous album Thank U, Next, &amp;ldquo;imagine&amp;rdquo; sets the tone with mesmerizing minimalism. Listen here. This official music video of imagine features mosaiced icebergs melting to fall. The song gives an impression of a breathtakingly beautiful abstract painting, when one looks more carefully, there is so much pain tangled within.
Imagine is an absolute masterpiece that particularly, adds depth to the album&amp;rsquo;s artistry. It employs a steady triple meter and firm beats to elegantly propel the flow forward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>get well soon</title>
      <link>/posts/get_well_soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 23:37:47 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/get_well_soon/</guid>
      <description>Listen to get well soon on YouTube for the official audio release or the unreleased vide available on Bilibili)
Get well soon (stylized in all lowercase) is the fifteenth and final track from Ariana Grande&amp;rsquo;s fourth studio album, Sweetener. The track is 5 minutes and 22 seconds long, paying respect to the Manchester bombing attack at Ariana’s concert on the 22nd of May 2017. There&amp;rsquo;s 40 seconds of silence at the end of the track, to commemorate those who lost their lives during the attack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>goodnight n go</title>
      <link>/posts/goodnight_n_go1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 22:58:52 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/goodnight_n_go1/</guid>
      <description>In the musical Hamilton (2015), in the song Satisfied, the rap verse, Angelica sang three reasons, literally &amp;ldquo;number one/two/three, &amp;hellip;blah blah&amp;rdquo; to illustrate why she loved but cannot marry Alexander Hamilton and she backed up for her sister. It was possibly the most unimaginatively boring lyrics ever written.
That is to say, when it comes to music, aside from serious discuss of production quality, vocal techniques or more general analysis, sometimes what matters most is appeals and feelings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sweetener</title>
      <link>/posts/jason~/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 21:57:47 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/jason~/</guid>
      <description>Listen here: Ariana Grande, “Sweetener”
The title track of Ariana Grande&amp;rsquo;s fourth studio album &amp;ldquo;sweetener&amp;rdquo; (stylized in all lowercase) the pivotal nomination in my top-10 Ariana Grande list. This album, Sweetener, won Grande a Grammy. The artist herself has elucidated the essence of the album&amp;rsquo;s title, suggesting it&amp;rsquo;s an ode to the act of illuminating one&amp;rsquo;s existence or circumstances, metaphorically &amp;ldquo;sweetening&amp;rdquo; life&amp;rsquo;s myriad challenges:
it&amp;rsquo;s kind of about bringing light to a situation or to someone&amp;rsquo;s life or somebody else brings light to your life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Focus!</title>
      <link>/posts/focus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:12:45 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/focus/</guid>
      <description>One, two three&amp;hellip; c&amp;rsquo;om, girls!
Focus is an Ariana Grande single yet it doesn&amp;rsquo;t belong to any of her studio albums:
The song was originally released as the lead single from Grande&amp;rsquo;s third studio album, titled Moonlight at the time. As the album&amp;rsquo;s concept changed and its title renamed to become Dangerous Woman, the song was removed from the main track list, including the standard and deluxe versions. In this process, &amp;ldquo;Dangerous Woman&amp;rdquo; replaced &amp;ldquo;Focus&amp;rdquo; as the lead single.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tattooed Heart</title>
      <link>/posts/tattooed_heart1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 23:41:46 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/tattooed_heart1/</guid>
      <description>Two songs from Ariana Grande&amp;rsquo;s debut album Yours Truly hold a special place in my heart, and they&amp;rsquo;ve earned their spots in my top 10 list. The first is &amp;ldquo;The Way&amp;rdquo;, and the other is &amp;ldquo;Tattooed Heart&amp;rdquo;. While &amp;ldquo;The Way&amp;rdquo; was an immediate hit upon release, &amp;ldquo;Tattooed Heart&amp;rdquo; gained recognition more gradually, especially after Grande performed it frequently in her later career, notably during her Sweetener World Tour.
The setlist of the Sweetener World Tour was strategically divided into three sections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>all &#39;The Way&#39; back</title>
      <link>/posts/the_way/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 22:49:46 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the_way/</guid>
      <description>The countdown is on: just ten days until the release of Ariana Grande&amp;rsquo;s seventh album, Eternal Sunshine. As a tribute to my favorite artist&amp;rsquo;s new musical chapter and to alleviate the recent turmoil of work, I&amp;rsquo;m dedicating a ten-day series on my blog to my top ten personal Ariana Grande songs.
My musical preferences have subtly evolved over time. Songs that once seemed mundane or whose acclaim puzzled me have, with time, revealed their allure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>will or should?</title>
      <link>/posts/want_or_have_to_do/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 22:38:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/want_or_have_to_do/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s pause for a minute of reflection today. Here&amp;rsquo;s the question:
In this moment, are the tasks you undertake today born of your heart&amp;rsquo;s desire, or are they mere obligations you&amp;rsquo;re bound to fulfill?
It&amp;rsquo;s just a binary question with at most four combination of answer, but it&amp;rsquo;s not easy to give a simple, definite response or even directly confront the truth for some people. Here&amp;rsquo;s one answer from Ariana Grande though, in her Vogue 19 cover interview</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>an artist&#39;s attitude | from Ariana Grande&#39;s Billboard cover story</title>
      <link>/posts/attitude/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2024 00:51:55 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/attitude/</guid>
      <description>There are conflicts happening every now and then. The best way is just to focus on something else. Because if one just gets distracted by all those negative things, he might as well doesn&amp;rsquo;t have anything more meaningful on his mind to do. It would be pathetic.
The attitude expressed by Ariana Grande&amp;rsquo;s billboard interview (almost 9 years ago) pretty much reflected this pov:
Grande’s determined to avoid any kind of controversy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freakonomics | Is Google Getting Worse? (Update)</title>
      <link>/posts/what_happened_to_google/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 00:21:02 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/what_happened_to_google/</guid>
      <description>The latest episode of Freakonomics podcast titled Is Google Getting Worse? (Update) covered a topic (sponsored search) that I thought I was familiar with, but after listening, found myself to be pondering with new thoughts. To begin with, the guest list of this episode is already unimaginably fantastic:
SOURCES Marissa Mayer, co-founder of Sunshine; former C.E.O. of Yahoo! and vice president at Google. Ryan McDevitt; professor of economics at Duke University.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a study of the lowercase aesthetic</title>
      <link>/posts/lowercase_aesthetic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 20:09:56 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/lowercase_aesthetic/</guid>
      <description>I prefer writing in all lowercases–especially devoid of conventional capitalizations of the first letters. First learnt this in Ariana Grande&amp;rsquo;s Sweetener album tracks&amp;rsquo; all-lowercase namings and initially trying just for fun, I found this way of styled writing extremely comfortable so that it eventually forms into a habit. This seemingly personal preference however, coincides with a latest trend of writing style, especially among Gen Z.
Ariana Grande&amp;rsquo;s iconic, abusive use of all-lowercase writings in her social media posts, do do her fans.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
