<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Sweetener on ariana&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/sweetener/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sweetener on ariana&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:53:31 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/sweetener/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>just like magic</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/just_like_magic2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:53:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/just_like_magic2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ariana Grande possesses a magnetic energy that attracts literally everything–from musical excellence to (possibly undesired) publicity. Among her songs, &amp;ldquo;just like magic&amp;rdquo; stands out as a testament to awe-inspiring confidence:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like magic, I&amp;rsquo;m attractive&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I get everything I want cause I attract them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a fine line between positive self-assurance and complacency. With her four-octave range and Mariah Carey-like whistle note capacity, Ariana Grande has never lacked a &amp;ldquo;hear-me-roar&amp;rdquo; attitude, reminiscent of &amp;rsquo;90s divas. She has consistently showcased an unshakable belief in herself, as heard in &amp;ldquo;Dangerous Woman&amp;rdquo;—&amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t need permission, made my decision, to test my limits,&amp;rdquo; and the resplendent &amp;ldquo;7 rings&amp;rdquo;—&amp;ldquo;I want it, I got it.&amp;rdquo; Early on, she was often described as &amp;ldquo;a small woman with a big voice and a huge personality.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>34&#43;35</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/34_35/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 23:59:50 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/34_35/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;means i wanna sixty-nine with yu, no&amp;hellip;shit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(mumbling) math class, never was good&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;– 34+35, &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Positions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Living under possibly the most draconian public scrutiny, Ariana Grande steered through the tumulous years of her rising music career accompanied by a terrorist attack during tour, several relationship melt downs, meanwhile delivered two of the best albums—and one of the highest-grossing tours—of 2018 and 2019. That she might finally be experiencing some release, which is what her return album in 2020 &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Positions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; sound like.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>needy</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/needy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 23:08:46 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/needy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thank U, Next&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; got two seats out of the top-10 list. One is &lt;a href=&#34;//localhost:1313/posts/imagine/&#34;&gt;imagine&lt;/a&gt;, the other is &lt;strong&gt;needy&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do hate overly simple songs: cloying melodies consisted of banal, unimaginative motifs  and too-obvious intentions are absolutely unforgivable. Referring the words of a professor&amp;rsquo;s architecture appreciation course I&amp;rsquo;ve taken two years ago, &amp;ldquo;sometimes overly obvious &amp;lsquo;signs&amp;rsquo; or too straightforward expressions, despite appealing, are degrading for art.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BUT &amp;mdash;- despite having shallow melodies (that one can literally anticipate the whole song after hearing the first few bars), needy sits on top of the list being simplicitly expressive and truthful. The song is about insecurities–of one&amp;rsquo;s attachment, obsession and struggle in a relationship–that Ariana Grande sang out in subjective tense, right out of the lyrics:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>imagine</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/imagine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 23:55:46 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/imagine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As the opening track of Ariana Grande&amp;rsquo;s tumultuous album &lt;em&gt;Thank U, Next&lt;/em&gt;, &amp;ldquo;imagine&amp;rdquo; sets the tone with mesmerizing minimalism. Listen &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/7_rftpd0u0U?si=8fAYMCzbEAuH2LYD&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. This official music video of imagine features mosaiced icebergs melting to fall. The song gives an impression of a breathtakingly beautiful abstract painting, when one looks more carefully, there is so much pain tangled within.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Imagine&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; is an absolute masterpiece that particularly, adds depth to the album&amp;rsquo;s artistry. It employs a steady triple meter and firm beats to elegantly propel the flow forward. The pre-chorus builds momentum with a gentle crescendo and chord progression. In the chorus, following the lyric &amp;ldquo;imagine a world like that,&amp;rdquo; which Ariana sings with extreme fortissimo and strength, the song falls into silence as if the question remains unanswered. It embodies &amp;ldquo;a simple, beautiful love that is now (and forever) unattainable,&amp;rdquo; serving as an unresolved plea for a fragmented, unrealistic dream.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>get well soon</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/get_well_soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 23:37:47 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/get_well_soon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Listen to &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;get well soon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/hXU4P6j3TNY?si=XIj_rbNIYPA1yGtv&#34;&gt;YouTube for the official audio release&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bilibili.com/video/BV1ac411M7ty/?spm_id_from=333.999.0.0&amp;amp;vd_source=047f1e1eeb7e14e77db36bbee08c35e5&#34;&gt;the unreleased vide available on Bilibili&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get well soon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; (stylized in all lowercase) is the fifteenth and final track from &lt;a href=&#34;https://arianagrande.fandom.com/wiki/Ariana_Grande&#34;&gt;Ariana Grande&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s fourth studio album, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://arianagrande.fandom.com/wiki/Sweetener_(album)&#34;&gt;Sweetener&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. The track is 5 minutes and 22 seconds long, paying respect to the Manchester bombing attack at Ariana’s concert on the 22nd of May 2017. There&amp;rsquo;s 40 seconds of silence at the end of the track, to commemorate those who lost their lives during the attack.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>goodnight n go</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/goodnight_n_go1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 22:58:52 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/goodnight_n_go1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the musical Hamilton (2015), in the song Satisfied, the rap verse, Angelica sang three reasons, literally &amp;ldquo;number one/two/three, &amp;hellip;blah blah&amp;rdquo; to illustrate why she loved but cannot marry Alexander Hamilton and she backed up for her sister. It was possibly the most unimaginatively boring lyrics ever written.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is to say, when it comes to music, aside from serious discuss of production quality, vocal techniques or more general analysis, sometimes what matters most is appeals and feelings. There are basically two kinds of &amp;lsquo;favourite&amp;rsquo; for a song. One is that you are able to name numerous reasons, that the song is an artistic marvel, topping the chart, being experimental etc.. Another version of favourite is that some song somehow becomes the go-to song on top of one&amp;rsquo;s mind. When I was picking out the top-k songs, compared to the ones that swing around the borderline that it takes a minute to decide whether it falls above or below the threshold, &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;goodnight n go&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; was picked directly out of the pool and stuffed into the second place among my all-time favourites.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sweetener</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/jason~/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 21:57:47 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/jason~/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Listen here:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;Ariana Grande, “Sweetener”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The title track of Ariana Grande&amp;rsquo;s fourth studio album &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;sweetener&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; (stylized in all lowercase) the pivotal nomination in my top-10 Ariana Grande list. This album, &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sweetener&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, won Grande a Grammy. The artist herself has elucidated the essence of the album&amp;rsquo;s title, suggesting it&amp;rsquo;s an ode to the act of illuminating one&amp;rsquo;s existence or circumstances, metaphorically &amp;ldquo;sweetening&amp;rdquo; life&amp;rsquo;s myriad challenges:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;it&amp;rsquo;s kind of about bringing light to a situation or to someone&amp;rsquo;s life or somebody else brings light to your life. Sweetening the situation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
