<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Classical on ariana&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/classical/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Classical on ariana&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 10:41:46 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/classical/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Horowitz&#39;s recitals</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/horowitz_recitals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 10:41:46 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/horowitz_recitals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Apple music classical has a marvelous collection of Vladimir Horowitz&amp;rsquo;s piano recitals—all the years, all the remarkable concert halls and performance:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;vladimir-horowitz-the-unreleased-live-recordings-1966-1983httpsmusicapplecomngalbumvladimir-horowitz-the-unreleased-live-recordings-19661063391589&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.apple.com/ng/album/vladimir-horowitz-the-unreleased-live-recordings-1966/1063391589&#34;&gt;Vladimir Horowitz: The Unreleased Live Recordings 1966-1983&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This recording CD costs minimum of $250 on Amazon, but now it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.apple.com/ng/album/vladimir-horowitz-the-unreleased-live-recordings-1966/1063391589&#34;&gt;free and available in highest possible stereo quality on Apple Music Classical&lt;/a&gt;. Run, Rach lovers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.apple.com/ng/album/vladimir-horowitz-the-unreleased-live-recordings-1966/1063391589&#34;&gt;Vladimir Horowitz: The Unreleased Live Recordings 1966-1983&lt;/a&gt; is an extensive collection of 50 CDs, documenting Horowitz&amp;rsquo;s live performances across 17 years. This set includes performances from the world&amp;rsquo;s most prestigious and iconic venues (mainly across the United States and Europe), including &lt;strong&gt;Carnegie Hall&lt;/strong&gt; in New York City, Constitution Hall in Washington, D.C., and the White House; and &lt;strong&gt;Royal Festival Hall&lt;/strong&gt; in London, for the queen.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Meeting of Titans – The Day Vladimir Horowitz and Sergei Rachmaninoff Arrived Together at Steinway Hall</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/horowitz_n_rach/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 10:14:35 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/horowitz_n_rach/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Steinway-piano dot com has the story of the meeting of the two perhaps most influential musicians among the piano community of the first half of the 20th century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;horowitz-the-rising-of-a-star&#34;&gt;Horowitz: the rising of a star&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vladimir Horowitz and Sergei Rachmaninoff had each suffered great losses in the Russian Revolution of 1917. “We lost absolutely everything,” Horowitz told author, radio personality, and Steinway Artist David Dubal, as reported in Dubal’s book, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://books.google.com/books/about/Reflections_from_the_keyboard.html?id=VfgXAQAAIAAJ&#34;&gt;Reflections from the Keyboard&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; “In 24 hours, all we had we lost.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zen and Art of Piano | Horowitz</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/zen_and_art_of_piano/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2024 09:49:44 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/zen_and_art_of_piano/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Horowitz, fire sings through metal, glass, water and &lt;em&gt;ice&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Carolina Philharmonic has the story &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;Zen and the Art of Piano | Vladimir Horowitz&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo;, by David Michael Wolff. It&amp;rsquo;s about the artistic style of &lt;strong&gt;pianist Horowitz&lt;/strong&gt; and his inspirational friendship with Rachmaninoff. The time was around the beginning of the 20th century—artists flee from the war and revolution in Russia to arrive in US:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The young Horowitz had just landed off the boat in NYC and with all the sights the New World had to offer, his first stop was Rachmaninoff’s Manhattan apartment. The next day they met at the now famed basement of Steinway Hall so that Rachmaninoff could hear what the young artist could do with his colossal Third Concerto. They played through the entire work at two pianos. Can you imagine what that must have sounded like - these twin giants of 20th century pianism - their languages blending and playing off each other!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Andante Cantabile II</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/rachmaninoff_andante_cantabile/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 23:52:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/rachmaninoff_andante_cantabile/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Andante Cantabile, generally means &amp;ldquo;singing and walking&amp;rdquo;, is a musical &lt;em&gt;term&lt;/em&gt;—a descriptive marker atop a score to delineate the mood or tempo intended by the composer. It . This trend is particularly poignant in compositions of grand scale, where each movement, each phrase, carries its own distinct &lt;em&gt;direction&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among the luminaries of the Andante Cantabile, Tchaikovsky’s String Quartet No. 1 in D Major resonates profoundly, a masterpiece that I&amp;rsquo;ve previously explored in &lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;an older post&lt;/a&gt;. Yet, even this pales in comparison to what may be the zenith of this expression:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
